Today, we're going to create a new Rails application and add this
このビデオでは、新しいRailsアプリケーションを作成し
free HTML dashboard theme we found. Besides the fact it has a lot of cool
無料のHTMLダッシュボードテーマを追加の仕方を紹介します。このテーマはすでに
graphs and dickey-doos, the theme is based on Bootstrap, so it's mobile friendly.
いろんなグラフがたくさん含まれているほか、ブートストラップ(Bootstrap)に基づいているので
Adding a Bootstrap theme to a Rails project is very simple, so let's get started.
Railsのプロジェクトにブートストラップのテーマを追加するのは非常に簡単ですので、さっそく始めましょう！
First, let's open up a command line window to create our Rails
最初に、ターミナルウィンドウを開いてRailsプロジェクトを作成しましょう。
project. We're going to name our project "bob".
プロジェクトには"bob"という名前をつきましょう
We can create our project by running the "rails new bob" command in the directory
プロジェクトを作るために適当なディレクトリに rails new bob
where we want our project to be created.
というコマンドを実行します。
Rails takes a few moments to generate all the base files for our project.
プロジェクトのすべてのファイルを生成するために、しばらくの時間がかかるかもしれません。
Once it's complete, let's verify everything is ok by starting a development
終わったら問題がないことを確認するためにHTTPサバーを起動しましょう。
Rails HTTP server on localhost. From the command line run
HTTPサバーを起動しましょう。ターミナルで
"bundle exec rails server"
"bundle exec rails server"
Now, open a new browser tab and go to your server's URl.
というコマンドを実行します。新しいブラウザタブを開いて
We can see the landing page that Rails generated for us.
生成されたRailsのデフォルトのページを見ることができます。
It displays information about the environment that our application is currently running in.
現在のアプリケーションを実行している環境に関する情報が表示されています。
Everything is working fine if we can see this landing page.
このデフォルトのページを見ることができればすべてが正常に動作しています。
Our first question: how do we see anything other than the default landing page that Rails provides?
質問：どのようにデフォルト以外のページを表示できますか？
The answer: by adding a route to our routes file.
答え：routes.rbファイルにルート(route)を追加します。
Every URL that Rails will respond to must be added to the routes file.
アプリケーションのページのURLのすべてがroutes.rbファイルに追加される必要があります。
Here's what we'll do. Open up the routes file
こうしましょう, routes.rbファイルを開きます.
Uncomment the root directive. We know we want
rootが定義されているコードのコメントを外してみましょう​。
a cool admin dashboard, so we'll rename this route to go to the Dashboards'
クールな管理ダッシュボードにするために、rootのルート(route)をダッシュボードコントローラー
index route. And save it. Let's refresh our app's browser tab.
とインデックスアクションの名前に変更してファイルを保存しましょう。ブラウザタブを再読み込みしてください
Notice the landing page is gone. It has been replaced by
デフォルトのページがなくなっていることに注意してください。かわりに
this lovely error message page. It points out that we have a routing error.
この素敵なエラーメッセージページに置き換えられています。ルーティングエラーとなっていることを示しています
The specific issue is that the DashboardsController is missing.
原因はDashboardsControllerが存在しないためです。
So, let's create our dashboards_controller
ダッシュボードコントローラと
and index [method]. In app/controllers directory
とインデックスを作成してみましょう。app/controllersのディレクトリで
we want to create a file named dashboards_controller
dashboards_controller.rbという名前のファイルを作成して 、
And in that file, we'll put the following code.
次のコードを書きましょう
The DashboardsController inherits from the ApplicationController which Rails
DashboardsControllerはすでにRailsに作られてあるApplicationControllerを継承します。
has already provided us. And our index action has no special logic
indexアクションは特別なロジックがないので
so we'll leave it blank.
なにも書く必要がありません。
Now we need to create a view for this action. In the app/views directory
次に、このアクション用のビューを作成する必要があります。app/viewsディレクトリで
create a folder named "dashboards" (plural) just like the controller and route.
コントローラーと同じ名前のdashboardsというディレクトリを作りましょう.
In there, add an index.html.erb
そのディレクトリの中にindex.html.erbのファイルを追加します
file then type in a short message like this.
次に、index.html.erbに、この短いテキストを入力しましょう。
If we save now, restart our rails server, and view the project in our browser
保存して、rails server を再起動し、ブラウザでプロジェクトを表示すると
We'll see the Dashboard's index view and our message.
ダッシュボードのインデックスビューとそのテキストが表示されます。
Great. Now it's time to add our Bootstrap theme.
今からBootstrapのテーマを追加してみましょう。
Most Bootstrap themes come with example HTML
ほとんどのBootstrapのテーマの中にはHTMLのサンプル
and all the CSS and Javascript nestled away in subfolders
とすべてのCSSとJavascriptがフォルダごと
following different naming conventions. That's not a problem for us.
に含まれています。今このままで置いておきましょう。
All we have to do is move our CSS to assets/stylesheets directory.
テーマのすべてのCSSをassets/stylesheetsのディレクトリにコピーします。
Any minified CSS we'll discard as long as we have the unminified version.
もし同じCSSで改行されたファイルと改行されていないファイルがあったら
Then, move the javascripts to assets/javascripts.
Javascriptをassets/javascripts/にコピーします
Just like the stylesheets, any minified javascripts we'll discard
CSSと同じように同じJavascriptで改行されたファイルと改行されていないファイルがあったら
as long as we have the unminified version.
改行されていないほうをコピーしてください。
And, move any images to assets/images.
画像ファイルをassets/images/にコピーします。
Finally, if you have any custom fonts
最後に、カスタムフォントがある場合,
just make a directory inside assets named "fonts" and put them in there.
assets/fontsというディレクトリを作成し、フォントをそこにコピーしてください。
Simple!
Simple!
Ok. Now we need to
HTMLのサンプルをビユーに利用します。
decide where to put this main theme file. I prefer keeping the
。一番簡単な方法としてrailsのレイアウト（app/views/layouts/application.html.erb）に利用できますが
original application layout file as simple and clean as possible, just to make it easier to swap
一つのアプリケーションでたくさんのテーマを使えるように
out themes in different parts of my application. The only thing I want
する方法としてレイアウトにHTMLは設定しません。
to do in the apps/views/layouts/application.html.erb
レイアウトではjavascript_include_tagのタグ
is to move the javascript include tag to the bottom
を今の場所からページのbodyの一番下に移動します。
Then, take all the body content from our Bootstrap theme demo file
つぎに、サンプルのHTMLの最初からj
excluding the javascript tags at the bottom
Javascriptが定義されている手前の行までを選択して
copy it, and paste it into the app/views/dashboards/index.html.erb
/app/views/dashboards/index.html.erbのファイルにコピーしてください
Save it, then refresh our application in the browser.
ファイルを保存して、ブラウザを再読み込みしてください
Wow, looks great. But there are a few things missing.
どうでしょう、素晴らしいように見えますが、不足していることもいくつかあります。
Using our browser's developer tools we can see what's broken, but
ブラウザの開発ツールを使うと何が壊れているかを見ることができます。
knowing how to fix it is a little more tricky. So here's the quick answer.
この問題を修正する方法ですが、少し裏技を使ってこうします：
FontAwesome's CSS file needs to be converted
FontAwesomeのcssファイルを
to an .erb file.
ERBファイルに変換してください。
so we can fix some paths using a Rails path helper.
こうするとRailsのパスヘルパーを使用して、パスを修正することができます:
Next we need to fix some of the javascript. We'll stub two of the javascript
次に、Javascriptの一部を修正する必要があります。ブラウザの開発ツールのコンソールで
files that are showing errors in our browser's developer tools console.
エラーが出ている二つのJavaScriptファイルをスタブします
These two files are demo files for the theme we downloaded.
これらの2つのファイルは、ただのデモファイルなので
We're going to turn them off by using this stub keyword. That will
スタブのキーワードを使用して無視するようにしても問題はありません。こうすると後からでも
leave them in the project so we can reuse them later. Stubbing just tells Rails to ignore them.
利用できるように、プロジェクトにファイルを残したままで、スタブのキーワードがそれらを無視するように指示します。
Now, refreshing our project in our browser shows no errors
ブラウザを再び読み込むとページはエラーを示めさず、
and everything appears to be here.
テーマがすべてちゃんとここに表示されています。
That's it for this lesson. Be sure to watch the additional related
これは今回のレッスンでした。RailsMania.comで共有している
content and advanced content we're sharing on RailsMania.com.
関連コンテンツやその他のより詳細なトピックをご覧ください。